Rockefeller Family Public Relations Department papers, Series 1-9 FA789A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), 1947-1961; 2; 7.98 Cubic Feet 21 letter document boxes
  - IBEC Housing Corporation (IHC), 1949-1957; 4
    - Puerto Rico - Commonwealth Development Corp. and Minillas Development Corp., 1955 (Box 24, Folder 252)
      IHC Major stockholder.
    - Puerto Rico - Highland Park Development, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 253)
      IHC Housing Project; roof leakage causing serious interior damage. Residents up in arms. Legislative subcommittee's airing of complaints from residents of Highland Park. Gerald Flamm, MD, Glen Lawrence, Saul Richman.
    - Florida Projects - Integration, 1949-1960 (Box 24, Folder 254)
      IHC unsuccessful attempts at building in Florida. 1956 Fort Lauderdale are project announced. 1957 "Margate" opened for purchasers. Brochures Christian Information Program. Question of integration in Margate, opinions, policy decision. George Dudley, MD, FAJ.
    - St. Louis, 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 255)
      Questioning whether to become associated with urban redevelopment building program in St. Louis. Decision not to go into project when St. Louis businessmen started plans for multi-story structures. St. Louis Post Dispatch articles. Fred Gardner, FAJ, MD, Al Goldstein.
    - Youngstown, Ohio, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 256)
      IHC to build 500 garden-type apts. Photos and floor plans. Mr. E. E. Swartswelter, William Reed, MD.
    - Norfolk, Virginia, 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 257)
      IHC in cooperation with Henry Clay Hofheimer II, Norfolk businessman, to build 204 housing units in low rent housing project. H. C. Hofheimer.
    - Other Projects, 1948-1952 (Box 25, Folder 258)
      Projects that were not undertaken: Caracas; Andrew's Field, Maryland; Belgium
    - H. F. Beir - Middle East Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 259)
      Reports on proposed Trans-Arabian Highway; on Kuwait Housing and Iraq Housing. Also reports on Iraq Government Development work; Saudi Arabia Salt; Dry Dock Situation; Saudi Arab Government Project; Tripoli Port Development. H. F. Beir; George Dudley.
    - Cinva-Ram Division, 1958-1960 (Box 25, Folder 260)
      IHC with Pan-American Union; contract to carry out development and world wide marketing of Cinva-Ram portable soil-cement building block press. Developed at the Inter-American Housing Center in Bogata, Colombia.
    - Corbetta Brothers - Release, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 261)
      Roger and Louis Corbetta elected VPs of IHC - In charge of Construction Division.
    - Movie - "The IBEC System of Low Cost Housing Construction", 1949-1951 (Box 25, Folder 262)
      Norfolk, Virginia houses done by Schuyler Bradt. Script draft. Schuyler Bradt, MD.
    - Films-KnickbockerProductions,Inc., 1957-1958 (Box 25, Folder 263)
      IHC in Lomas Verdes, Puerto Rico and Margate, Florida; project shelved indefinitely. Script drafts. Howard Lesser, George Dudley, Howard Knowles.
    - IBEC Realty Corporation - Redman and Ridgeway, 1956-1957 (Box 25, Folder 264)
      Puerto Rican shopping centers, Redman and Ridgeway operating in Continental USA as consultants to IBEC Realty. Jerry Flamm, R. W. Hisle, MD
  - IBEC Research Institute (IRI), 1950-1960; 5
    - General, 1950-1958 (Box 25, Folder 265)
      Established in 1950. A division of American International Corp. Improve standard of living by increasing efficiency of agricultural production (tropical and sub-tropical). Non-profit. Jerome F. Harrington, Dr. Robert P. Russell, A. E. Stuntz, FAJ, F. P. Mehrlich.
    - Finances, 1953-1957 (Box 25, Folder 266)
      RBF Pledge 1953; Creole Petroleum conditions on contributions. Budgets, financial statements. Dana Creel, J. W. Hisle.
    - AIA-IRI Merger, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 267)
      IRI merged into AIA to effect savings and organizational simplifications, details. L. H. Levy, Louise Boyer, John Campbell.
    - Brazil, 1951-1960 (Box 25, Folder 268)
      Report on seed impregnation work in Brazil; IRI housing in Brazil, A. Jones Report. Brazilian press comment - analysis, Dr. Damon Boynton Report. Robert Russell, MD, Arthur Jones, F. P. Mehrlich, FAJ, J. E. Lockwood.
    - Brazil - Animal Nutrition Center - Proposal, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 269)
      Department of Agriculture of State of Sao Paulo, Brazil asked IRI join with it in answering problem of providing greater availability of foodstuffs through more efficient agricultural production.
    - Brazil - George Soultanides, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 270)
      IRI employee. Soultanides claiming Harrington's IRI administration fraudulent, much to do. Richard Greenebaum, MD.
    - Venezuela - General, 1951-1954 (Box 25, Folder 271)
      Financing of IRI's activities in Venezuela by Creole. IRI's rice and corn experiments and programs 1954 programs for future. Robert Russell.
    - Venezuela Information Program, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 272)
      Information re rice and corn programs - by bulletins, memoranda, visits, lectures, demonstrations, etc. to agricultural research groups and representatives of major agricultural chemical manufacturers.
    - Venezuela - Public Education Program, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 273)
      To appeal to (1) scientific and technical groups and (2 ) farmer, by pictures, pamphlets, bulletins.
    - Venezuela - Press Comments and Reports, 1951-1956 (Box 25, Folder 274-275)
      Favorable and unfavorable from papers, i.e.. La Esfera, El Nacional, El Universal, La Calle. Robert Russell, FAJ.
    - Venezuela - Corn Program, 1952-1954 (Box 26, Folder 276)
    - Venezuela - Rice Program, 1957-1960 (Box 26, Folder 277-278)
    - INDUSSA Corporation, 1952-1955 (Box 26, Folder 279)
    - Publications - Dr. John B. Griffing, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 280)
      IRI commissioned "Da" Griffing to do various scientifically based articles and books re implications of work of IRI in Brazil and Venezuela. Several reports, articles, etc. by him. Termination of services.
    - Publications, 1951-1959 (Box 27, Folder 281-284)
      Bulletins re various reports on IRI's agricultural experimentation; 1 set as complete as is available, extra copies.
    - Published Articles, 1951-1956 (Box 27, Folder 285)
    - Report - Institute of Venezuela Herbicide Program, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 286)
    - Report - Venezuelan Chemical Weed Control, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 287)
    - Report - Coffee Research in Brazil, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 288-289)
    - Report - Memorandum Regarding Possible Increase in Scope of IBEC Research Institute Activities, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 290)
    - Report - Summarizing Memorandum Regarding Status of Venezuelan Programs, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 291)
    - Report - Experimental Programs in Brazil, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 292)
    - Report - Mulching Young Coffee in Brazil, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 293)
    - Report - Progress Report to Trustees - Brazil, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 294)
- Administration and Staff, 1947-1961; 3; 5.32 Cubic Feet 14 letter document boxes
  - Summaries of Activities, 1956-1957 (Box 29, Folder 295)
    Summary of PR activities for IBEC Research Institute; monthly activity reports made to FAJ
  - Document, Policy, Guide Manual, 1947-1957 (Box 29, Folder 296-297)
    Employment policies in Venezuela. Programs and Policy development for IBEC and AIA. Development of PR manual for IBEC and AIA
  - Staff Memos, 1951-1960 (Box 29, Folder 298)
    Changing assignments of staff members functions of office.
  - Ivy Lee - JDR, Jr. Biography, 1949-1957 (Box 29, Folder 299)
    Office comments on biographies prepared by T. J. Ross in 1949-1955 and 1957. Copies of biography here.
  - Amelia Lobseny, 1957-1961 (Box 29, Folder 300-301)
    Outside public relations advisor. Reports. Museum of Primitive Art, Worked on Special Studies NAR politics.
  - Richard W. Boogaart - Argentina, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 302)
    Member of IBEC staff in supermarket venture; publicity problems concerning local merchants and import duties.
  - Schuyler Bradt - CBR - Venezuela - Costa Rica, 1956-1959 (Box 29, Folder 303)
    Organizer and director of Agricultural Information Program; training programs for Venezuela personnel; radio broadcasts done from records; "Juancito" comic books; 1958 unrest in Venezuela
  - Enrico Bustos- Venezuela, 1956-1960 (Box 30, Folder 304)
    Advertising and merchandising Manager for IBEC. Todos Supermarkets; advertising programs, supermarket improvement programs and public relations efforts; local competition; report on trip, supermarkets new locations, progress reports.
  - John R. Camp, 1947-1961 (Box 30, Folder 305-306)
    Head of Mission to Venezuela; organization of IBEC office, supervision of operations and programs; progress reports, press releases in local papers; transportation problems; proposed organization to help provide technical services; publicity problems and recommended methods of reaching the masses. Camp comments on "Partners in Progress", relations with Government. CIDEA, CBR relations with oil companies. Political unrest, changes in program in 1960.
  - William Coles, 1947-1961 (Box 30, Folder 307)
    IBEC counsel in Caracas. Relations with government and oil companies. Organizing companies. DR Venezuelan land proposal.
  - Steven David, 1960-1961 (Box 30, Folder 308)
    Brief Reports from Italy, Norway and Latin America
  - H. W. Bagley, 1950-1961 (Box 30, Folder 309-310, Box 31, Folder 311-317, Box 32, Folder 318-324, Box 33, Folder 325-328)
    Handled PR for IBEC and AIA in Sao Paulo, Brazil. Reports. of political conditions in Brazil, press coverage of company activities. Impact of programs in Brazil. Preparation of serial articles on programs. Robert Moses reaction to criticisms of his Sao Paulo study. Brazilian comments on Supermarkets. Changing operations of IBEC and AIA in Brazil Internal differences. Jamiesons death.
  - H. W. Bagley - Brazil - Cumbica Land, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 329)
  - H. W. Bagley - Brazil - Government Communists, etc., 1951 (Box 33, Folder 330)
  - H. W. Bagley - Roundup Report, 1956-1961 (Box 33, Folder 331)
  - H. W. Bagley - Press Clipping Summaries, 1956-1961 (Box 33, Folder 332)
  - H. W. Bagley - Coffee, 1950-1958 (Box 33, Folder 333)
  - Gerald R. Flamm, 1956-1958 (Box 34, Folder 334-339, Box 35, Folder 340-342)
    Puerto Rico public relations for IBEC. IBEC housing, supermarket plans. Press releases, advertisements. Labor problems, competition. Management of Todos turned over to Grand Union in 1959. Flamm' s criticisms of organizational policies. Resigned, 1961.
    - Tape of Interview Local English-Language Radio, circa 1957-1958; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15819)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Gerald R. Flamm - El Imparcial - Rockefeller Family, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 343)
  - Gerald R. Flamm - Puerto Rican Labor Situation, 1958-1959 (Box 35, Folder 344)
  - Gerald R. Flamm - TODOS Little League Team, 1957-1958 (Box 35, Folder 345)
  - Dee Jackson - Brazil, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 346)
  - John B. Griffing, 1951-1956 (Box 35, Folder 347-348)
    Agricultural expert employed by AIA in Brazil. Wrote articles describing and explaining experiments, French silos, hybrid corn, coffee production.
  - Francis A. Jamieson - Personal, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 349-350)
    Staff assignments. Eben Ayers comments on White House, 1952. Rodman Rockefeller on draft, comments on work in Peru (1952). William Coles on politics. Invitations. Changing problems in the office. His oral history at Columbia. Comments on NAR' s political career.
  - Francis A. Jamieson - Death, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 351)
  - "The Reminiscences of Francis A. Jamieson", 1959 (Box 36, Folder 352)
    Oral History Office, Columbia University
  - Bernardo Jofre, 1947-1948 (Box 36, Folder 353-354, Box 37, Folder 355-361, Box 38, Folder 362-366)
    PR representative in Caracas,"VBEC". Supermarkets. Milk processing and distribution. Management changes. Shopping centers. Political changes in Venezuela. "Yankee Imperialism" criticized.
  - Bernardo Jofre - Labor Relations - Venezuela - V. Borella, 1950-1958 (Box 38, Folder 367)
  - Bernardo Jofre - Nelson A. Rockefeller Letter - Executives and Company Managers, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 368)
  - Bernardo Jofre - Governor Rockefeller Trip to Venezuela - Clippings, 1959 (Box 39, Folder 369)
  - Bernardo Jofre - Venezuela - Political Situation, 1949-1961 (Box 39, Folder 370)
  - Bernardo Jofre - Venezuela - Milk, 1953-1955 (Box 39, Folder 371)
  - Bernardo Jofre - Colombia and Panama, 1954-1955 (Box 39, Folder 372)
  - Bernardo Jofre - Puerto Rico, 1954-1955 (Box 39, Folder 373)
  - Bernardo Jofre - El Salvador, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 374)
  - Bernardo Jofre - Releases, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 375)
    Oil Company Deal, Maracaibo and Caracas Shopping Centers
  - Bernardo Jofre - VBEC/CADA - Oil Company Commissaries, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 376)
  - Bernardo Jofre - Peru, 1952-1956 (Box 39, Folder 377)
  - Saul Richman, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 378)
    Reports from Venezuela
  - Nelson Riley, 1946-1961 (Box 40, Folder 379-381)
    FAJ describes program and purpose of AIA to Riley; Riley worked in CIAA during war. Employed to work in Venezuela and Brazil. Reports on political conditions in Brazil. Intra-company problems. Public relations policies. Shift to Venezuela and New York.
  - Martin H. Reynolds, 1951-1959 (Box 40, Folder 382-383)
    Employed in CIDEA in Venezuela. Distribution of nutrition stories to Venezuelan press. Cartoon publications. Political changes. Expanding the program. Problems.
  - A. E. Stuntz, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 384)
    Prepared book on work on Institute of Inter-American Affairs. NAR financed some of the studies. Jamieson comments on books. Hired by NAR organization in 1948 to work in nutrition program in Venezuela (CIDEA). Visual aides used in program. Book published 1948 "To Make the People Strong". Internal policy problems. Moved to Florida in IBEC housing 1957-1958 as part time employee. Question of integrated housing.
  - A. E. Stuntz - Personal, 1948-1955 (Box 40, Folder 385)
  - A. E. Stuntz - AIA/CIDEA - Venezuela, 1948-1953 (Box 40, Folder 386)
  - A. E. Stuntz - IHC Florida, 1957-1958 (Box 41, Folder 387)
  - A. E. Stuntz - "To Make the People Strong", 1947 (Box 41, Folder 388-390)
  - Lewis L. Strauss, 1950-1953 (Box 41, Folder 391)
    Biographical file on LSR associates.
  - A. H. Vandenberg, Jr., 1949-1950 (Box 41, Folder 392)
    Public relations in Sao Paulo, Brazil. Intra-company problems. Family illness forced him from job.
  - Radio - Television (Box 41, Folder 393)
- General - United States, 1946-1961; 4; 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1949-1952 (Box 42, Folder 394)
    DR letter to members of the board re. land purchase of Property Building near United Nations; activities.
  - Carnegie Endowment - General - David Rockefeller, 1950-1958 (Box 42, Folder 395)
    Correspondence with Public Relations department; Alger Hiss trial, publicity.
  - Carnegie Endowment - Cox Committee - Coates and McCormick, 1951-1952 (Box 42, Folder 396)
    Memos re. Citizens Committee for the Hoover Report; Coates and McCormick, Inc.; Coates and McCormick, Inc. engaged to do Public Relations on Endowment's position in the investigation of the Cox Committee.
  - Carnegie Foundation, 1950-1951 (Box 42, Folder 397)
    Correspondence re. Point IV; Carnegie Endowment program, trustees.
  - Pablo Casals - Concert, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 398)
    Concert - Israel Tourist Office at house of Peggy and David Rockefeller
  - Chock-Full-of-Nuts Commercial, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 399)
    Objections to use of name in coffee commercial
  - Corry, Andrew V., 1951-1955 (Box 42, Folder 400)
    Formerly with Office of Inter-American Affairs, then in India for State Department; comments on internal political situation in India; friend of NAR.
  - Dodgers, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 401)
    Efforts to keep the Brooklyn Dodgers in New York.
  - Ford Foundation, 1950-1954 (Box 42, Folder 402)
    General statement about AIA - what it is, method of operation, relations to technical assistance programs of the United States Government and the United Nations; fields for expansion; memo of conversations at Ford Foundation; draft of proposal for Ford Foundation program in underdeveloped areas of South America; family contacts with the Ford Foundation.
  - Hanson, Simon G., 1950-1951 (Box 42, Folder 403)
    Hanson's Latin American letters.
  - Institute for International Social Research, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 404)
    Proposed announcement of formation of Institute; NAR becomes member of board.
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1952 (Box 42, Folder 405)
    Recommendation that JDR 3rd decline to attend conference; DR report on IPR
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1953-1955 (Box 42, Folder 406)
    Problem of increasing numbers of delinquents, proposed 5-day institute to study various aspects, commission on juvenile delinquency.
  - Labor - General, 1947-1958 (Box 42, Folder 407)
    Information on labor unions in Latin America, anti-Point IV Program propaganda; comparing unionism in Latin American; U.S. investment abroad.
  - National Citizens Planning Convention - Little Rock, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 408)
    WR participation in the Conference, "Main Street, 1969"
  - National Conference on Metropolitan Problems, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 409)
    Draft of general report, NAR presided, evaluation of conference.
  - Pocantico Hills - Deer Hunting, 1960-1961 (Box 42, Folder 410)
    Arrangements to thin wild deer running on estate.
  - Puerto Rico, 1954-1958 (Box 42, Folder 411)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1951-1958 (Box 43, Folder 412)
    PR comments on possible REF projects. META, Billy Graham, NYC Teachers Program, NYC Police.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund - Annual Report, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 413)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund - Protestant Ministers Economic Security, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 414)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund - Publishing Reports, Doubleday and Co., 1957-1960 (Box 43, Folder 415)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund - Reports, 1954-1959 (Box 43, Folder 416-417)
    Press releases and reports.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund - Sam Rayburn Foundation, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 418)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Special Studies, 1956 (Box 44, Folder 419-422)
    Panel members minutes of some panel meetings. Writing the reports. Comments on drafts of reports. Publication policies. Distribution of reports.
  - Rockefeller Brothers, Inc., 1946-1952 (Box 44, Folder 423)
    1947 Procedure manual. Press statements prepared on organization.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Cox and Reece Investigation, 1953 (Box 44, Folder 424)
    Foundation testimony before Congressional investigation committee
  - Rockefeller Institute, 1954-1958 (Box 45, Folder 425-426)
    York Avenue Redevelopment plan 1956. Public relations program for Rockefeller University. Rockefeller diet. Scattered publications.
  - Rosenberg, Anna - Office of I. Berezin, 1947-1961 (Box 45, Folder 427)
    Telegrams from NAR, LSR, DR recommending Senate confirmation of AR; correspondence with Irving Berezin; statements praising AR; proposed press release re IBEC qualification in Brazil; recommendations for NAR on book about progressive capitalism.
  - Saarinen, Aline, 1956-1959 (Box 45, Folder 428)
    Correspondence re. her book The Proud Possessors; notes re. NAR and art and museums.
  - Standard Oil Company, 1948-1961 (Box 45, Folder 429)
    Life chart on Standard Oil families, "The Standard Oil Co." 75th Anniversary, alleged discrimination.
  - Tarrytown, New York, 1952-1959 (Box 45, Folder 430)
    Recommendations concerning local organizations and relationships of family with them; Tarrytown Daily News press release arrangements.
  - United Tarrytown Committee, 1950 (Box 45, Folder 431)
    Rockefeller support of effort to continue two Tarrytown's into one government. Efforts defeated in 1950.
  - United Nations, 1947-1958 (Box 45, Folder 432)
    NAR decline to Mead Provisional Committee in support of the Marshal Plan after failure of 3 Power Conference in Paris; U. N. public relations problems; recommendations re. invitations to serve; DR member of Advisory Board on Investment; contributions made. Layout for U. N. site documents, text, photographs made of U. N. documents; Copies of letter of December 17, 1946 in connection with selection of East River site.
  - Veterans - Miscellaneous, 1952-1953 (Box 45, Folder 433)
    Recommendations re. awards, invitations; NAR chairman of Jewish War Veteran's dinner December 28, 1952; NAR honorary member of American Veterans Committee; DR declines to join Chase Bank Post of American Legion.
  - Westchester County, 1951-1961 (Box 45, Folder 434)
- General - Foreign, 1947-1961; 5; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - Africa, 1956-1961 (Box 46, Folder 435)
    Recommendations concerning South African venture; memos to files re. Rockefeller interests in Africa.
  - Asia, 1953-1958 (Box 46, Folder 436)
    Suggested program in Agricultural economics in Southern Asia; Ideas for Economic Aid to Asia; recommendations concerning invitations to serve or contribute; Afro-Asian Conference, 1955, JDR 3rd Asia memo to C. Douglas Dillon.
  - Asia House - Asia Society, 1956-1959 (Box 46, Folder 437)
    Formation of Asia Society; questionnaire done for Conference on Asian Affairs; membership drive; recommendations made re. Asia Society programs, brochures.
  - Japan, 1951-1956 (Box 46, Folder 438)
    Memos re. organizations interested in Japan, Japan-U. S. Relations, Japanese Americans; possible projects in Japan; recommendations made.
  - Japan - Newspapers, 1952-1960 (Box 46, Folder 439)
    Recommendations re. statements to news media.
  - Japanese Peace Treaty - Dulles Mission, 1951 (Box 46, Folder 440)
    Report to Ambassador John Foster Dulles; summary of report called "United States-Japanese Cultural Relations"; requests from the press for interview or statements; JDR 3rd statement on ratification of Japanese Peace Treaty; preliminary report to Dulles February 26, 1951; cable sent to Ambassador Sebold in Tokyo re. new rights and responsibilities of the women of Japan.
  - The Japan Society - General, 1952-1959 (Box 46, Folder 441)
    Background information on board members and candidates; recommendations re. broadcasts and invitations; programs and activities. Crown Prince of Japan visit and dinner September 17, 1953 Preparation of press releases; planning dinner.
  - The Japan Society - Crown Prince of Japan Visit, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 442)
  - Latin America - American, 1956-1961 (Box 46, Folder 443)
    Recommendations concerning invitations and participation in establishment of various organizations, memos re. politics and economics in S. America.
  - Lee Selvage and Chase (Samuel B. Bledsoe), 1952-1956 (Box 46, Folder 444)
    Public Relations interests in the filed of Latin America. (Bolivian government).
  - Brazil - Government, 1953-1961 (Box 46, Folder 445)
    Plan for reorganization of Brazilian government; Brazilian elections; information about Juscelino Kubitschek; handling of Brazil press criticisms; oil interests; Brazilian press luncheon; Brazilian ore negotiations; political and economic trends in Brazil; recommendations re. invitations and requests.
  - Romulo Gallegos, 1947-1948 (Box 46, Folder 446)
    Recommendations made; Truman-Gallegos film "For This We Live" made during visit to U.S. in July 1948; luncheon at Columbia University.
  - Juscelino Kubitschek, (Mr.. and Mrs. .), 1952-1961 (Box 46, Folder 447)
    Correspondence between FAJ and Henry Bagley; NAR gift to Mrs.. Kubtschek's Organizacao das Pioneiras Sociais refused as it was considered not large enough; memos to NAR re. Kubitschek.
  - Venezuela - General, 1948-1961 (Box 47, Folder 448-449)